# **Barkha Patel**

4 Dayton Drive Edison
New Jersey-08820
732-925-5677
barkhaptl14@gmail.com/barkha1388@gmail.com

## **Aspiration**

I am an energetic, attentive and reliable professional offering more than 10 years of experience fulfilling various administrative functions and teaching skills. I have been a part of academics wherein I have had the chance to present my creativity and communication skills. My strength lies in the spontaneous approach and a touch of humor that I bring to any conversation or discussion. Practiced exemplary planning and organizational skills while maintaining a consistent positive attitude. Possess a proactive work ethic along with meticulous attention to detail when processing paperwork, handling inquiries and concerns. My passion for educating can help me achieve the zenith in this field and explore the wide range of opportunities that are in store for me and my hidden talent.

# **Professional History**

### **Private Tutor (Since June 2008 - Present)**

- Coaching ICSE, CBSE, IB and GSEB students from grades 1st to 10th.
- Providing study materials and mock test papers.
- Preparing assignment sheets.

## **Jesam Institute (June 2009 to September 2013)**

#### Office Administrator:

- Enrolled and directed the students and leading the center.
- Overseeing daily activities of teachers and other staff.
- Monitoring financial affairs.
- Supervising teachers.
- Ensuring proper implementation of curriculum.
- Assigning teaching schedules.
- Answered telephone routine inquiries and prepare mails out letters of acceptance to all new students.
- Maintained log of inquiries as required.
- Operated a personal computer to draft basic correspondence data entry.
- Making receipt for tuition payments.

- Perform a variety of routine typing materials and copy materials as requested.
- Order books as well as prepare notes for classes.
- Maintaining accurate academic records.
- Contacting parents of students with failing grades or disciplinary issues.
- Helping with problem-solving between teacher and parents.
- Counseled students on nearly every aspect of a social and professional life.
- Assisted the center head with events like organizing picnic, celebrate days, appreciation events etc.

### A-One School (October 2013 - April 2016)

#### **Science Educator:**

- Teaching Science from grades 5<sup>th</sup> to 9<sup>th</sup>.
- Preparing worksheets, tests and exam papers.
- Created and implemented science lesson plans for students in the 8<sup>th</sup> and 9<sup>th</sup> grade.
- Ability to teach the various science levels (Physics, Chemistry and Biology)
- Applying different methods for the improvement of the students.
- Incorporated PowerPoint presentations into lessons to reinforce key points.
- Using continuous improvement process to make impressive lessons.
- Willingness to go beyond what is expected to ensure that each student grasps the concepts taught.
- Prepared and developed lesson plans and instructional programs to every individual.
- Administered practice exams to enhance students' skills.
- Bringing out the educational experiments to capture students.
- · Pedagogical ability
- Hosting various events in the school.
- Served at the school's science department and coordinated with administration for the organization of events.
- Spearheaded science fairs and projects.
- Assisting students with the escalation process.
- Supervising during board exams.
- Fun committee member for the staff.
- Actively participating and mentoring children for annual functions.
- Arranging outdoor tours and exhibitions for children along with the committee.

### **VWEC- Vakratund World Education Center (May 2016- October 2016)**

#### **IELTS Trainer:**

- Teaching General English and IELTS programmes.
- Applying different methods for the improvement of the students.
- Using continuous improvement process to make impressive lessons.
- Pedagogical ability.

### RN Inspire Services Pvt. Ltd. (May 2017- July 2017) Free Lance

#### **Soft Skills Trainer:**

- Teaching Grammar.
- Facilitating day-to-day classes to assist students in giving knowledge and soft-skills needed to secure employment.
- Demonstrating and understanding of teaching materials and procedures with understanding of various teaching methods.
- Instructing students in job seeking, application procedures and resume writing.

## Thinkcell Learning Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (June 2018 – December 2018)

#### **Student Relations Executive:**

- Trained and coached to have a general understanding of programs, processes, fee structure and other key information.
- Encouraging students to make decisions and set their own reasonable goals.
- Communicated with prospective students and enrolled students via phone and email.
- Responsibility of providing accurate, consistent and timely information to the students.
- Maintained a student retention rate by providing best service by linking education to careers.
- Provided educational guidance and assistance to students by confidentially counseling students on challenges and personal obstacles.
- Planned, coordinated and maintained student's schedule of classes and worked with students to resolve scheduling conflicts.

## Edit Systems Pvt Ltd - Silica Institute (January 2019- December 2019)

## **Education Coordinator cum Counselor:**

- Prepare and maintain documents for education plans and implement and maintain all administrative work.
- Prepare and maintain the comprehensive records for education programs and monitor students growth.
- Observe and maintain record of children's progress and maintain transition procedures for all the candidates.
- Assist in admission process and monitor all direct mailings and phone and respond to student's information requests.
- Coordinate with managers to prepare conference schedule and participate in various training events.
- Develop and monitor center's educational programs and plan education events and participate in seminars and workshops and coordinate with various departments.
- Evaluate the applications for candidates and manage all applications and assist in orientation programs.

### M Square Media Pvt. Ltd. (March 2020- September 2022)

## **Service Manager:**

- We are a service provider who fills the gap between the students and Universities offshore for the students who want to study in states or other countries.
- Regular updation of collective data on the company's online portal.
- Responsible for supervising the employees and their daily operations within the department.
- I had to create daily reports and send it to higher management by the end of the day.
- Responsible for overseeing the communication between my Admission team and the University Staff.
- Addressing any issues faced by my team and providing appropriate solutions to every escalated matters.
- Responsible for auditing if the timelines were met for every step related to the admission procedure.
- Delivering prompt and professional solutions for student inquiries and team's queries.
- Training and managing new admission staff in professional service practice.
- Held weekly Google meets and zoom meetings with the team and University Staff.
- We closely worked with the Agents and students to apply for the applications on our portal.
- Keeping a close watch on each and every University by maintaining data on Excel.
- High attention to detail and ability to multi-task.
- Extremely organized and able to prioritize workload.

## **Didactic Competence**

Degree	Institute	University/Board	Result	Grade	Year
B.Sc. in Chemistry	St. Xavier's College	Gujarat University	56%	Pass Class	2009
H.S.C	C. U. Shah High School	Gujarat Board	66%	First Class	2006
S.S.C	Trinity English School	Gujarat Board	81%	Distinction	2004

# **Key Skills**

- Remarkable ability to demonstrate problem solving and decision making skills.
- Excellent office management and analytical skills.
- Data entry and documentation.
- · Customer service.
- MS Word, Excel and PowerPoint.

## **Extra Skills**

- Qualities of leadership and ability to give best in team work.
- Crafting, sketching and painting.
- · Photography.
- Presentation and communication with clarity and spontaneity.

# **Linguistic Ability**

• English, Gujarati and Hindi

## **Personal Details**

**Date of Birth:** 13 June 1988

Nationality: Indian

**Gender:** Female

Marital Status: Married

# **Declaration**

Hereby I declare that the information mentioned here in my resume is correct and complete to best of my knowledge and nothing has been concealed or distorted.

**Barkha Patel**